Guide to the Bushnell Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bushnell family papers
1713-1908
MS 118
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
Chiefly legal papers of various members of the Bushnell family of Saybrook, Conn. relating to the purchase of land and other financial transactions. The compositions of Lydia O. Dibble, a cousin of Ida Bushnell, include an essay on the death of a friend (1848).
Bushnell family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
A small amount of the papers were transferred from the Yale Divinity School; the remainder was given by an unknown donor in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged by family member.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists chiefly of legal papers of various members of the Bushnell Family of Saybrook, Connecticut. Most of the legal documents relate to the purchase of land and other financial transactions. Also included are the compositions of Lydia O. Dibble, a cousin of Ida Bushnell.
A small amount of the Bushnell Family Papers were transferred from the Yale Divinity School. The majority were received from an unknown donor in 1969.
Death; Families; Connecticut; Saybrook (Conn.); United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; Bushnell family
- Inventory
  - Bushnell, Joshua (1690-1767)
    - ADS, deed for land sold to Samuel Bushnell, 1713/14 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 2 ADS, deeds for land sold to Samuel Bushnell, 1720 December 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clarke, John. ADS, re: Nathaniel Bushnell's discharge from the army and wounding, 1729 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bushnell, Nathaniel. ADS, record of the survey of his land in Saybrook, 1752 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Knap, Samuel. ADS, receipt for money obtained from Samuel and Stephen Bushnell, 1713/14 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bushnell, Samuel. ADS, powers of attorney to Daniel Bushnell, 1720 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bushnell, Stephen (1653/4-1727)
    - ADS, bond for money to be paid to the Rev. Moses Noyes, 1716 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - ADS, deed for land sold to Nathaniel Bushnell, 1723/24 January 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - ADS, agreements between Stephen and Sarah Bushnell and Nathaniel Bushnell, 1724/5 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clarke, John. ADS, appraisal of the estate of Thomas Bushnell, 1714/15 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bushnell, William. ADS, re: [exchange of land?], 1714/1715 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Buckingham, Daniel. ADS, deed for land granted to Joseph Lynde, 1743 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lord, Benjamin. DS, deed for land sold to Joseph Lynde, 1745 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - AD of unknown authrship identifying signatures in this colletion as beloning to men prominent in the Saybrook disturbance over the removal of Yale to New Haven (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bushnell, Edward L. ALS to Henry E. Bushnell requesting payments to Ida M. Bushnell, 1908 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bushnell, Ida. Birthday poem, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bushnell, Aaron. Obituary on his death, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dibble, Lydia O. (cousin of Ida Bushnell) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Composition book and diary, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "Emma Alayn, or the friend of my early days", 1848 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dibbell, Joseph [d. 1869]. Account book for goods and services (1757-1769) and inventory of his estate, 1769 Jul 7, Saybrook, Conn. The book is continued by his son, Josiah Dibble, with accounts from 1769 to 1795. Among the second Josiah Dibble's accounts is a bill for medical treatment (1787-1795) by Dr. John Ely. Also included is a list of the Necessaries allowed Josiah Dibble's widow," n.d., 1757-1795, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)